-= 字幕制作：jndxtmr@disanlou.org =-
你们好
Hello.
我来自围墙之外
I come from outside the wall,
在那儿 人们相互摧残
where we have all but destroyed each other.
把你们的城市设计成实验室
We designed you city as an experiment.
是因为坚信这是重拾人性的唯一途径
And we believe it is the only way to recover the humanity we have lost.
我们创建了派系来维护和平
And we created Factions to ensure peace.
但我们也相信 你们当中肯定有人
But we believe there will be those among you
能超越这些派系
who will transcend these factions,
他们将是分歧者
these will be the Divergent.
是这场实验的真正目的
They are the true purpose of this experiment,
对人类的存亡至关重要
they are vital to humanity survival.
如果你们正在看这段视频 说明至少有一个人
If you are watching this now,then at least one of you is proof
证明了实验是成功的
that our experiment has succeeded.
是时候
The time has come
从你们封闭的城市里走出来了 加入我们吧
for you to emerge from your isolation and rejoin us.
奉伊芙琳之令 马上关闭城门
On Evelyn's orders:This gate is now closed!
我们曾让你们相信自己是最后的幸存者
We've allowed you to believe that you’re the last of us,
其实不是
but you’re not.
其他人类正在围墙外满怀希望地等待着你们
Mankind waits for you with hope,beyond the Wall.
分歧者3：忠诚世界
我们快到了
We're almost there.
对 我在你后面
Yeah, I'm right behind you.
我说你不会恐高吧
What are you,afraid of heights?
不 谁跟你说的
No.Who told you that?
有时候我朝围墙外面看
Sometimes when I look past the wall,
感觉自己能看到外面的东西
I think that I can see something out there.
你呢
Do you?
我 看不到
No.I don't.
也许你得看仔细点儿
Maybe you need to look harder.
我正看着呢
I am looking.
可还是什么都看不到
I'm just not seeing what you see.
如果在眼前 你就看到了
When it's right in front of your face, you will.
我们真的要离开吗
You sure we're going to do this?
对
Yeah.
芝加哥的全体公民
People of Chicago,
我知道你们很好奇围墙外面有什么
I know you are curious about what's beyond the wall,
但有的时候围墙是在保护我们
but sometimes walls are there to protect us.
记住 正是那些创建者把我们划分成了若干派系
Remember, the founders were the ones who divided us into Factions.
所以在我们不知道他们的真实目的前 城门必须关闭
So, until we know their intentions,the wall must stay closed.
珍宁已经死了
Jeanine is dead.
今天 我们要开始审判她的同谋者
Today, we begin the trials of her conspirators.
审判叛徒 关闭城门
Put the traitors on trial,close down the gate.
没想到 她这么快就走上了珍宁的老路
Didn't take her long to make the same mistakes as Jeanine.
我得和她谈谈
I need to talk to her.
我想我能劝她回头
I still think I can bring her around.
但那改变不了任何事
But that doesn't change anything, right?.
不
No.
我要你帮我弄点儿东西
I need you to get somethings for me.
就这个
Just this?
确定不再摘个太阳月亮什么的
You sure you don't want the sun and moon as well?
- 我知道这很困难  - 简直是不可能
- I know it's a lot. - It's impossible.
- 所以  - 所以只有我能搞定
- So? - So, I'll make it happen.
你们好 女士们
Well.Hello, ladies.
要去哪儿 能一起吗
Where are we going?Can I come?
- 滚远点儿 皮特  - 太不友好了
- Give it up, Peter. - Why so hostile!
派系都没了 我们能成朋友了 对吗
There's no faction.We can be friends, right?
难道就不能相亲相爱吗
Can't we all just get along?
翠丝
Tris.
你应该上去跟其他领导者在一起
Your should be up there with all the other leaders of the city.
不 我可不想 去制定什么规矩
No, it's not me.I don't want to make the rules.
伟大的领导者从不追逐权力 他们被社会需求所召唤
Great leaders don't seek power,they're called by necessity.
人们需要你
They need you.
看着我 你这个叛徒
Look at me!Look at me, traitor!
- 准备好去死了吗  - 后退
- You're going to die in there! - Back up.
准备好去死了吗
You're going to die in there!
快走
Move!
待在这儿
Sit tight.
我们都在新环境中找到了自己
We all find ourselves on new ground.
我毕生的志愿就是追寻真相 但珍宁却让我错过了它
I dedicated my life to seeking the truth,but under Jeanine, it passed me by.
为此 我真诚向诸位道歉
And for that,I humbly apologize.
但是我失败的教训 更坚定了我纠正自己错误的决心
But my personal failure has only strengthened my resolve to make things right.
即使现在诚实派不复存在了
While the Faction of Candor may no longer exist,
我也想让大家知道 我不会停下追求真相的脚步
I want everyone to know that I will not stop leading the pursuit of honesty,
让我们携起手来 重建家园
as we rebuild our city.
- 好  - 好
- Yay! - Yay!
审判现在开始 让我们来伸张正义
Let the trials begin!Justice will be done!
- 好  - 好
- Yay! - Yay!
来吧
Here.
愿真相让你解脱
May the truth set you free.
毫无疑问 你协助珍宁接管了芝加哥
There's no doubt, Max, that you helped Jeanine take over Chicago,
对人民进行了残忍的控制
and exert brutal control over it's citizens.
我唯一想问的就是你觉得
So, my only question to you is this.
屠杀人民去支持她的政权是否正确
Did you feel justified in murdering people in support of her regime?
当然正确
Absolutely.
人民是绵羊 他们需要牧羊人引导
People are sheep.They need a shepherd to guide them.
如果他们反抗 就该被杀
And when they resist,they're slaughtered.
禽兽
Monster.
我们应该杀了你
We should slaughter you!
杀了他
Kill him!Kill him!
- 杀了他  - 别杀他
- Kill him! - Don't kill him!
- 别杀他  - 杀了他
- Let him live! - Kill him!
- Let him live! - Kill him now!
理智点儿
Rise above it.
你们不能这样做 快停下来
You can't do this, stop it!
别杀他 我们跟那些杀人犯不一样
Let him live!We're better than this!
理智点儿
Rise above it.
珍宁
Jeanine!
珍宁已经死了
Jeanine is dead!
我们不能再重蹈覆辙了
Let's not keep her spirit alive.
- 杀了他  - 别杀他
- Kill him! - Let him live!
现在怎么办 得给他们个交代
What are you going to do?They need an answer.
这是一场杀戮
This is an execution.
不 这是一场审判
No.This is a trial.
我服从全体公民的意愿
And I yield,to the wishes of the people.
是时候打破历史的牢笼了
It is time,that we break from the past!
好
Yay!
杀了他
You need to die!
我还不想死
I don't want to die.
你杀的人也不想
Neither did your sheep.
过去我说过 我愿你们活在爱里 而不是恨里
There was a time I would have said:I leave you with love, not malice.
看来过去已经过去了
That time has passed.
- 杀了她  - 叛徒
- Kill her!  - Traitor!
杀了她
Kill her!Kill her!
叛徒
Traitor!
出去
Get out! Out!Get out! Out!
Get out!Out!
碧翠丝 对不起
Beatrice!I'm sorry!
你煽动了民众 但愿你能掌控得住
You incited a mob.Good luck controlling them.
碧翠丝 求你了 别让他们杀了我
Beatrice, please!Don't let them kill me!
碧翠丝 不
Beatrice!No!
碧翠丝
Beatrice!
你知道你在做什么吗 我们得表现得团结一致
What the hell did you think you're doing?We need to show a united front.
尤其是在碧翠丝拒绝跟我们同一阵营之后
Especially, since Tris refuses to stand with us.
- 我不会告诉她 她该干什么  - 你得试着跟她说
- I'm not going to tell Tris what to do. - Well, you need to try!
你真的认为自己能阻止人们离开这座城市吗
Do you really think that you can stop people leaving this city?
城门现在已经锁上了 我的士兵们听从我的
The wall's on total lock down,my soldiers have orders.
没人能出去
No one gets out.
你为什么要跟珍宁开战
Why did you go to war with Jeanine,
难道只是想变成她
if you were just going to become her?
领导者们为了保护人民需要作出艰难的决定
Leaders need to make tough decisions to protect their people.
等你继承了我的位置自然就会明白了
You'll understand that when you take over from me.
我这都是为了你
I'm doing this for you.
现在可能不是离开的最佳时机
You know, it might not be the best time to leave.
那也不能待在这儿解决所有冲突
I know, but we can't be here for every fight.
信息里也说要走出去面对新世界
And the message said to come out and meet the rest of the world .
可我们对传递信息的人一无所知
Yet, we know absolutely nothing about the people who sent it.
那你就不想把她找出来吗
Aren't you curious to find out?
我们的家园怎么办
What about our home?
我觉得我们的家园已经不复存在了
I don't think our home exist any more.
也许走出去反而能够帮到芝加哥
Maybe the way to help Chicago is climb beyond the wall.
可万一外面什么都没有 荒芜一片呢
What if there's nothing out there?What If there is nothing left?
只要你在我就能活下去 但你必须得让我试一试
I can live with that if you are with me,but I can not live without trying.
你知道明天要审凯莱布吧
You know, it's Caleb's trial tomorrow.
是 我知道
Yeah, I know.
可我没觉得有什么欠他的
I don't owe him anything.
没错 你不欠他
No.No, you don't.
我来处理这个人
I'm going to deal with this one.
你觉得我是在请求你吗
Do you think I'm asking your permission?
不 求你了 老四 不要
No, please.No, Four. No!
老四
Four.Four.
求你了 别杀我 对不起
Please don't kill me!I'm sorry!
老四 对不起
Four, I'm sorry!
连自己亲妹妹都想杀 你这是作死
You tried to kill your own sister, Caleb.You brought this on yourself.
对不起 我向你道歉
I'm sorry, for everything.
快点儿 我们上去
Come on.We're going up.
快点儿
Come on.Come on.
- 碧翠丝  - 慢点儿走
- Beatrice? - Walk slowly.
嘿
Hey!
所有博学派的犯人都应关在牢里
All Erudite prisoners are suppose to be locked in the cages.
站住
Stop!
我自己能处理这个人
I can handle this one myself.
带他们进来
Bring him in!
你现在能出来了
You can come out now, Caleb.
谢谢你 老四 谢谢
Thank you, Four.Thank you.
不用谢我 是你妹妹的主意
Don't thank me.It's your sister's idea.
你救了我
You saved me?
这才是家人该做的
It's what you do for family.
上车吧
Get in the car.
我就知道
I knew it.
伙计们
Hey, partners.
你来这干什么 皮特 离开这儿
What are you doing, Peter?Get out of here.
没错 我正准备要离开这儿
Yes, that's what I'm doing,I'm getting out of here.
听着 在你妈妈肆意妄为的时候
Look, I don't want to be here when your crazy mom
我可不想留在这儿 她会整死所有为珍宁做过事的人
goes around killing everybody who used to work for Jeanine, okay?
听着 要么现在就让我加入你们 要么
Look, I can join you guys or I could...
我就大喊 救命 他们要跑了
Yell: Help! Help! Help!They're getting away!
嚷嚷什么 消停会儿行吗 上车 皮特
Get in the car, Peter.Get in the car.
- 就等这句话呢  - 上车
- That's what I'm saying. - Get in the car.
谢谢
Thank you.
还好吗 凯莱布
What's up, Caleb?
没错
Yeah!
我们要听真相
We want the truth!
他死定了 对 快杀了他
He's dead. Yeah.Hurry up and kill him.
伸张正义
Justice for all!
你已经有计划了是吧
You do have a plan, right?
我没接到任何转移犯人的通知
I didn't hear anything about a prisoner transfer.
我刚刚通知过你
Well, you're hearing it from me.
请出示转移令
Let me see your movement order.
在这儿呢 在我这儿
I got it!Right here!
这是转移令 把门打开
I got everything.So, open the gate.
再来一个 快点儿 好 埃德加
One more, come on.Come on, one more. Yeah!
托比亚斯·伊顿把凯莱布·普勒尔带走了
Tobias Eaton took Caleb Prior out of his cage.
快点儿 我们走 快
Come on.Let's go, now.
快点儿 再审几个
Come on!Let's do some more!
你是雕塑吗
You a statue?
快开门
Open the gate.
他们从这儿走的
Have they come through here?
我们离开这儿
Let's get out of here.
他们跑了
They're getting away.
托比亚斯·伊顿带着凯莱布·普勒尔逃跑了 他也成了反叛者
Tobias Eaton is abetting Caleb Prior's escape.That makes him a traitor.
杀了他
Shoot to kill.
任何人不得翻越围墙 这是命令
No body goes over that wall.We have our orders.
好了吗
Ready?
好了
Yeah.
跟书本上学的不太一样
Not the same as reading in the books, huh?
好了 没有危险
Okay, coast is clear.
是时候走出去了
It's time to see what's out there.
好了 跟紧我
Okay.On me.
该死 发射 抓钩
Shit.Release now!
我去帮他
I got him.
抱歉 老四
I'm sorry, Four.
快点
Come on.Come on.
克里斯蒂娜
CHRISTINA !
- 我没事  - 这也是计划的一部分
- I'm okay. - That part of the plan, Stiff?
伊芙琳给围栏通了电
Evelyn electrified the fence.
我们成功了
We did it.
托莉
Tori.
Tori. Tori!Tori!
天哪 托莉
Okay, Tori.
快点儿 我们得离开这儿
Come on, we got to go.Come on!
不 托莉
No!Tori!
托莉
Tori.
上车
Come on, load up!
好了 我们走
Alright, let's go.
快点儿 这边
Come on.This way!
我的天哪
Holy shit.
这儿发生过什么
What happened here?
根本没为你准备欢迎仪式 僵尸人
Didn't exactly sent out a welcome committee for you, Stiff.
闭嘴
Shut up, Peter.
人类满怀希望地欢迎你们 人在哪儿呢
Humanity welcomes you with hope.What humanity?
这个水坑看起来好像有放射性
This hole looks radioactive.
至少得有200年了
Or at least it was so in the last 200 years.
这能说明什么问题
Meaning what exactly?
有人毁了这个世界
Somebody seriously messed up the world.
该死
Shit.
真给力 天空都流血了
Great.Now the sky is bleeding.
这边走
This way!
快点儿 我们走
Come on, let's go!
跟紧了
Now, come on.
真好玩 把自己给玩了
This is fun.I'm glad we did this.
万一什么都没有呢
What if there's nothing else out there?
一定会有的
There has to be.
我害怕
I'm scared.
我想 这是正常反应
Yeah, I think that's a good thing.
听到了吗
You guys hear that?
- 是引擎  - 有人来找我们了
- It's an engine. - Someone's coming for us.
- 是埃德加 快跑  - 快
- It's Edgar. Go, go! - Come on!
跑 快跑 那边跑 快
Go, go!Turn back, go!
霍利斯 不 霍利斯
Hollis! No!Hollis!
天哪 这是 这是什么
Who, what is this?
别害怕 不用担心
Don't be afraid,there's nothing to worry about.
你们现在安全了
You're safe now.
欢迎你 老四
Welcome, Four.
翠丝·普勒尔 很荣幸见到你
Tris Prior, it's an honor to meet you.
你怎么知道我名字
How do you know our names?
什么情况
What the?
欢迎来到你们的未来 我们一直在等你们
Welcome to the future.We've been waiting for you.
等离子球会把你们和有毒的环境隔离开
Our plasma globes will protect you from the toxicity.
嗨
Hey.
- 我们现在安全了  - 对
- We're going to be okay. - Yeah.
看啊
Look.
不可思议
This is incredible.
简直太疯狂了
This is insane!
天哪 超赞
Get out.
她是翠丝
It's Tris.
欢迎你们来到基因福利局 我是马修
Welcome, to the Bureau of Genetic Alter.My name is Matthew.
现在 你们将被送进净化区
Now, let's get you into decontamination.
那个就是她 翠丝·普勒尔 她终于来了
That's her, Beatrice Prior.She made it.
什么都不用担心
There's nothing to worry about.
它会把你们身上沾染的我们世界的毒素清洗掉
You're being decontaminated from the toxins which plague our world.
请把你们的衣服脱了 然后丢进焚化炉
Please remove your clothes and place them in the incineration hatch.
上前一步
Please step forward.
站在标记上
Place your feet on the mark.
搞定了
You're clean.
请把手放进墙上的孔道里
Please place your arm into the tube in the wall.
不用有任何顾虑 翠丝
There's nothing to worry about, Tris.
请把手放进孔道里
Please place your arm into the tube.
这辈子都没这么干净过
I've never felt so clean in my life.
这是我洗过的最奇怪的澡了
That was the best weird shower I've ever had.
有点儿冷 但是
A little cold thou.
你的文身不一样
Hey, yours is different.
为什么都不一样
Why they are all different?
你们好 欢迎各位光临基因福利局
Hello, and welcome to the Bureau of Genetic Welfare.
在21世纪上半叶 科学家们首次发现并绘制了
In the early part of the 21st century,scientists first discovered a way to map
改变人类基因组的方法
then edit the human genome.
你能选择保持自身的基因组 也能选择改善它们
You can choose to settle from "merely adequate" or you can choose "excellent".
基因解决方案让你可以掌控自己的生命
A genetic solution puts you in control of your life.
为什么不期待一个更美好的未来 当你有机会选择完美时
So, why just hope for a better future,when you can choose perfection?
请选择蒲飞霞
Choose Perfexia.
但是正如试图清除人类的缺陷一样
But, what started as an attempt to erase humanity's fault,
人性也几乎被抹杀了
almost erased humanity itself.
基因改造加剧了人们之间的分歧
Genetic modification deepened the rifts between people.
当矛盾越来越深 世界便开始四分五裂
And as they got more entrenched,the world began to tear apart,
人类也因无法恢复原始基因 而变得无可挽救
until humanity crossed a line,from which it could never return.
在这片文明的废墟上
In the ashes of civilization,
一小群基因未被改造的人 建立了你们今天所在的这个基因福利局
a small group of genetically unmodified individuals established the "BUREAU OF GENETIC WELFARE."
在这儿 芝加哥的奥黑尔机场
here in Chicago's O'Hare Airport.
我们的任务是监控一项重要的实验
Our mission is to oversee a grand experiment
其目的就是净化人类的基因组
to purify the human genome.
而实验室就是芝加哥市
That experiment is the city of Chicago.
你们参与到了基因局的工作 就意味着成为了人类未来的守护者
Your participation in the Bureau's work means you are now the guardians of the future.
你们的使命从今天开始
Your destiny begins today.
现在请跟我来
Now.Please follow me.
机场是什么鬼
What's an airport?
在这儿生活限制很多
Life in the Bureau can be demanding.
但是我们值得为此付出
The work is worth every sacrifice.
基因局并不是要什么就有什么
We don't have all the resources we would like of course,
但足以满足你们的基本生活
but I think you'll find your accommodations more than adequate
他们是真人啊
They're in person, here.
- 他们是谁  - 从边界带回来的
- Who are they? - We bring them in from the Fringe.
等他们治好了 就能活下去了
Get them healthy.Give them a second chance.
老四
Hi, Four.
嗨
Hey.
他们怎么知道我们的
Now they know who we are.
实验室是整个基因局的焦点
The experiment is the entire focus of the Bureau.
我们的监控技术领先你们芝加哥几个世纪
Our Surveillance Technology is centuries ahead of anything you know in Chicago.
他们看着你们长大
They grown up watching you.
你可吓着我们了
Nothing creepy about that.
请原谅所有人都盯着你们看
You have to forgive everyone for staring, but...
但你们的到来对我们来说是件大事
your arrival is the most exciting event some of us have ever known.
欢迎来到新家
Welcome to your new home.
老四在哪儿 伤着他了吗
Where's Four?Did you hurt him?
我说过我要他们几个毫发无损
I told you I wanted them unharmed.
跟他们走了 是自愿的
He went with them.Willing.
- 他还活着吗  - 你没听懂吗
- But he's alive. - Did you hear what I'm saying?
他背叛了你
He betrayed you.
不
No...
- 都是因为爱情  - 他是你儿子
- It's just love. - He's your son.
他应该忠诚 像我这样
He should be loyal.I'm loyal!
没错 你很忠诚
Yes, you are!
去休息吧 我要你做好战斗准备
So, rest up.I need you ready to fight.
想什么呢
What do you think?
他们研究了我们200年 我们得迎头赶上
I think they've been studying us for 200 years and we need to catch up.
我们得抓住机会 对吗
We're going to give it a chance, right?
没错 完全正确
Yep,of course we are.
真想单约你
I wish we were alone.
打扰一下 我们头儿说要见你
Excuse me.The Director's ready to see you.
不 对不起 我说的是翠丝
No, I'm sorry.I mean Tris, alone.
不能一起去吗
We can't go together?
因为你是那个打开盒子的人
Since you were the one who opened the box which invited you here.
所以我们头儿想亲自感谢你
The Director would like to thank your personal.
一会儿见
I'll see you later.
- 衣服  - 谢谢
- Clothes. - Thanks.
这边请
This way.
来吧 手腕放在扫描仪上
Go ahead.Put your wrist under the scanner.
允许 进入
Access granted.
纯净
Pure.
我从没想过还有比芝加哥大的地方
I just never imagined the world to be this big.
在北美 芝加哥只是过去50个大城市
Chicago is just one of 50 major cities that used to exist
之中的一个
on this continent along.
除此之外 还有一望无际的海洋和广袤的大陆
Beyond that is, oceans and more land than you can imagine.
现在都变样了
But it's all like this now?
对
Yeah.
除了普罗维登斯
All except for Providence.
所以我们在这儿做的事非常重要 翠丝
Which is why what we're doing here is so important, Tris.
你好
Hello.
- 你一定是头儿了  - 拜托 叫我大卫
- You must be director. - Oh, please call me David.
很高兴我终于见到你了
It is a pleasure to finally meet you.
你一定有很多的疑问
You must have so many questions.
我有点儿不知所措 我还在试着理解
I'm a bit overwhelmed.I'm still processing it and all.
翠丝 我了解你
Oh.Tris, I know you.
你一出生我就在观察你
I watched you being born.
我看到了你父母对你的爱
I saw the love that your mother and father had for you.
看到了一个拥有幸福童年的小姑娘是如何成长为
I watched a little girl have a happy childhood and grow into a courageous young woman
一名勇敢而果断的女孩
capable of making choices.
加入无畏派 推翻珍宁
Dauntless.Defying Jeanine.
拯救芝加哥
Saving Chicago.
对人民你是分歧者
To your people,you are a divergent.
对委员会 你是怪胎
To the Council, you're a freak.
对我 你就是个奇迹
To me,you are a a miracle.
大卫 你注意到芝加哥现在发生的事了吗
David. are you-are you aware what's happening in Chicago right now?
注意到了 当然
Of Course.Yes.
博学派的人真是够可以的
The people at Erudite really made a mess of things,
但我不想你为这些担心
but I don't want your to worry about that.
恢复芝加哥的秩序对你和我都很重要
Restoring order in Chicago is as important to me as it is to you.
这是拯救缺陷者的唯一办法
It's the only way to save the "damaged".
什么是缺陷者
What is the "damaged".
基因改造产生了严重的后果
The genetic alterations had disastrous consequences.
太勇敢会变得残忍 太平和会变得懦弱
Too brave and you're cruel.Too peaceful and you're passive.
太聪明会变得冷酷 就像你哥哥
Too smart, and you'll lose compassion,like your brother.
- 凯莱布是缺陷者吗  - 没错
- Caleb's "damaged"? - Yes.
近200年来
For nearly 200 years,
顶尖的科学家们在这儿验证一个理论
the greatest scientific minds have lived here to test a theory.
如果我们能把边界地带
If we can rescue genetically damaged people
有毒环境中的基因缺陷者
from the toxic environment in the Fringe.
放在像芝加哥这样安全的城市里
and put them in a safe place like Chicago,
也许久而久之 人们的基因就能治愈自己
then perhaps over time,man's genetic material would heal itself.
这样就可以回到原来的样子了
Return to its original form.
我就是其中的一个
And I'm one of those people?
你是唯一的一个
You're the only one.
你这么说没道理 我是说
That doesn't- That doesn't make any sense
老四也是分歧者 还有很多分歧者
Four is divergent.There's lot of divergences.
不是分歧者 翠丝 是纯净者
Not divergent, Tris.Pure.
你是基因纯净者 其他人都是缺陷者
You're genetically "pure".The rest are still "damaged".
- 老四呢  - 缺陷者
- Four? - Damaged.
不像凯莱布那么严重 但也是缺陷者
Not as much as Caleb,but "damaged".
如果我们能知道是什么治愈了你
If we can understand what made you,
也许我们就能帮助其他的缺陷者了
maybe we can use that knowledge to help the "damaged".
但这跟芝加哥有什么关系
What does this have to do with Chicago?
我会向委员会汇报
I answer to the Council.
他们是最终决定我们命运的人
They're the ones who ultimately determine our fate.
你们的和我的
Yours and mine.
我准备带你去见他们
I'm going to bring you with me to Providence to meet them.
当他们看见这是有可能的 你就是那个可能性
When they see that it's possible,that you were possible,
一切都会改变
it will change everything.
我明白我的话很难得到信任
I understand it's hard to take my word for it.
但是如果你不相信我 就相信你母亲
But, if you don't believe me,believe your mother.
我母亲
My mother?
你母亲娜塔莉不是出生在芝加哥
Your mother, Natalie,wasn't born in Chicago.
她出生在边界地带 然后被基因局救了
She was born in the Fringe and rescued by the Bureau.
不 这根本不可能
No, that's impossible.
眼见为实
See for yourself.
这是什么
What are these?
这是你母亲的记忆卡
They're your mother's memory tabs.
有了这些你就能通过她的眼睛去看世界
With them, you can watch the world through her eyes.
我该怎么做
What do I do?
在太阳穴上各放一枚
Place one on each temple.
娜塔莉 快点儿
Natalie, come on!
我不是娜塔莉
I'm not Natalie.
我们得藏起来 快点儿
We need to hide!Come on!
他们来了 快跑
They're coming!Run!
是边界掠夺者
The Fringers!
快跑
Run!
边界掠夺者
The Fringers!
我不是娜塔莉
I'm not Natalie.
娜塔莉 不
Natalie, no!
不
No!
基因局的士兵
Bureau soldiers!
左边 左翼包抄
Left!Flank left!
打右边
Keep right! Keep right!Keep right!
我们带你到基因局 你安全了
We're taking you to the Bureau.You're safe.
不用再担惊受怕了
You don't have to be afraid anymore.
- 今天你又救了多少孩子  - 不够多
- How many more did you save today? - Not enough.
永远都不够多
We never get enough.
芝加哥必须发挥作用 大卫 这是我们唯一的希望
Chicago has got to work, David.It's the only hope for us.
在这片文明的废墟上 一小群基因未被改造的人
From the ashes of civilization, a small group of genetically unmodified individuals
建立了你们今天所在的这个基因福利局 在这儿 芝加哥的奥黑尔机场
established the Bureau of Genetic Welfare,here at Chicago's O'Hare airport.
你安全了
You're safe.
其目的就是净化人类的基因组
a grand experiment,to purify the human genome.
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
你们的使命 从今天开始
Your destiny begins today.
翠丝
Tris.
在危急关头 你母亲做了一件
In a moment of need,your mother did something
从没有人做过的事
that no one had done before.
她自愿离开安全的基因局
She volunteered to leave the safety of the Bureau
让自己加入到实验中
to enter the experiment herself.
她做这些是因为她知道应该拯救缺陷者
She did this because she knew the "damaged" were worth saving.
她非常相信实验 所以她自愿加入到实验中
She believed in the experiment so much she was willing to be a part of it.
如果我让委员会看到你这个奇迹可以被复制
If I can show the Council your miracle can be replicated,
那么她一生的工作就圆满了
then her life's work is complete.
委员会将不得不公平地对待每个生命
The Council will be force to look at any human being,
不管他们来自哪儿
No matter where they were born,is worthy of life.
帮帮我 你救了一座城市
Help me.You saved a city.
再帮我救救这个世界吧
Help me save the world.
太不可思议了
It was amazing.
好像我变成了她 并通过她的眼睛看到了一切
It was like I was her and seeing it all through her eyes.
我还是不能相信我妈妈来自这儿
I still can't believe my mom is from this place.
我理解你妈妈为什么要离开了
Well, I can see why she left.
你相信他吗  大卫
Do you trust him?David.
我相信妈妈
I trust her.
没错
Yeah.
禁止进入
Access denied.
翠丝
Tris.
允许进入
Access granted.
你来了 准备好了吗
Here you are.You ready?
替我问候大卫
Say hi to David for me.
托比亚斯·伊顿
Tobias Eaton.
你分给我负责了
You've been assigned to me.
我是妮塔 我们走
I am Nita.Let's go.
为什么不是所有人都能上来
Why isn't everyone allowed upstairs?
这是委员会众多规定中的一项
That would be one of the Council's many rules.
我也没办法
Certainly not mine.
这是隔离 我不喜欢
The Separation, I don't like it.
我同意 这些到最后都是多余的
I agree, and in time,that won't be necessary.
翠丝 我不知道是谁告诉你与众不同是件坏事的
But Tris, I don't know who told you that being different is a bad thing.
因为我知道不是你母亲
Because I know it wasn't your mother.
我知道能复制你的基因图谱 只是时间问题而已
Now I know I can replicate this.All I need is time.
听着 雷吉娜 我们得谈谈 你看上去像个好人
Look, Regina, let's talk.You seem like a nice lady, but...
但我真的不适合坐办公室
I'm really not a desk job kind of guy.
我有幽闭恐惧症
I get claustrophobic.
我得待在开放的地方
I need to be where the action is.
监视工作就是要密切关注
The job of Surveillance is to keep tabs
芝加哥日益动荡的局势
on the developing situation in Chicago.
这工作绝对放得开
This is where the action is.
海斯 这是你的监控室 普勒尔 你在隔壁
Hayes, this will be your pod.Prior, you're next door.
抵抗运动日益激烈 伊芙琳势必会有所行动
Resistance is growing.Evelyn is beginning to respond.
密切监视 然后提交报告
Watch what's happening,file a report.
等等 天哪 我刚从芝加哥逃出来
Wait. What... Hold on.I just escaped from Chicago.
现在你却要我后半辈子
Now you're saying, I got to sit here and watch it
都待在这儿监视它 和他一起
for the rest of my life?With Caleb?
也许你更愿意被驱逐到边界地带
Perhaps you prefer to be banished to the Fringe?
这儿的监控技术太不可思议了
Ah.This Surveillance technology is incredible.
- 造它的人肯定是天才  - 谢谢你
- Whoever created it, is a genius. - Well, thank you.
能热爱你的工作
It was a labor of love.
马屁精
Ass kisser.
保持热情 普勒尔
Keep it up, Prior.
还有你 开始工作
And you, get to it.
火力够充足的
It's an awful lot of firepower.
边界地带危机四伏
The Fringe is full of dangerous people.
穿上这个
Put this on.
- 这是什么  - 私人无人机
- What are these? - Personal drones.
它能扩大视野 为你构建周围环境的3D模型
Expands your field of vision and provides 3D modeling and environments.
就像过去在无畏派一样
Just like old times in Dauntless, huh?
除了没有过时的东西以外
Except there is nothing old about any of this.
给你
Here.
谢谢
Thanks.
激活头盔
Activate the head gear.
左手激活无人机
The left hand activates the drones.
[扫描]
ID: 老四
还能做别的吗
Does it do anything else?
不太多
Not much.
也就是用无人机找找目标
Use the drones to find the targets.
你需要花些时间才能熟悉它
It will take you a while to get the hang of it.
好的
Yeah.
明白了
Okay.
目标确认
Identified.
[扫描]
目标已经确认
Target Identified.
我想我已经熟悉了
I think I got the hang of it.
我能问个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
- 当然 问吧  - 如果我母亲出生在边界地带
- Yeah, of course. - If mother was born in the Fringe,
那她是怎么到芝加哥的
then,how did she end up in Chicago.
我是说你不可能把她送到了城门口吧
I mean, you couldn't just sent her through the gate, right?
不 不是
No.
委员会总是很谨慎地安置新人到实验室里
Now, the Council's always careful how they introduced any new element to the experiment.
他们需要时就会介入
Right. But, when they need to,they intervene.
没错
Yes.
那为什么现在还不介入呢
So, why aren't they intervening now?
他们会的 只要我们能说服他们
They will.We just have to make our case.
- 我能相信你会帮助我吗  - 当然
- Can I still count on you to help me? - Yes.
我能相信你吗
Can I count on you?
珍宁是绝没有机会打败你的
Jeanine never had a chance against you.
我们越快做好准备 就能越早去普罗维登斯
The sooner we get finished,the sooner we leave for Providence.
忠诚者 你们这么称呼自己吗
The Allegiant.That's what you're calling yourselves.
友好派这个称呼已经不再合适了
Amity just doesn't seem appropriate anymore.
那么你们到底忠诚于什么呢 派别体系吗
So, what exactly are you allegiant to?The faction system?
派系在很长时间里维持了芝加哥的和平
The factions kept Chicago peaceful for a long time.
我并不了解这个 因为我被迫离开了自己的派系
Well, I wouldn't know about that because I was forced out of my faction.
我放弃了我的生活 我的孩子 所有的一切
I gave up my life,my child, everything.
我理解你的愤怒 伊芙琳 真的
I understand your anger,Evelyn, I do.
- 但是未来的路  - 未来的路已经铺好了
- But the way forward... - The way forward has already began.
我说过我会一个人来
I know I said I'd be alone,but...
但我不是诚实派 也不是友好派
I'm not Candor and I'm not Amity.
所以我撒了谎 如果有必要的话我还会战斗
So I will lie and I will fight if I have to.
看见这些伤疤了吗 我不是出生在友好派
You see these scars?I wasn't born Amity.
我能向你保证 我并不害怕为信念而战
And I can assure you I'm not afraid to fight for what I believe in.
看来我们是同一类人
It seems like we're 2 peas in a pot.
但并不一定非要用这种方式
But it doesn't have to be this way.
我们可以好好商量
We can come to some sort of agreement.
- 退后  - 蹲下
- Get back! - Get down!
- 离开这儿  - 我们走
- Get out of here! - Let's go.
快走
Go!
听着 凯莱布
Alright, Caleb.
万一情况有变通知我好吗
Keep me posted if anything changes, alright?
凯莱布说无畏派的一些人站到了约翰娜这边
Caleb said that some of the Dauntless are lining with Johanna.
但剩下的诚实派还和伊芙琳一个阵营
But the rest of Candor are still solid with Evelyn.
局势就快失去控制了
Things are  finally out of control.
大卫说过他能做什么吗
Did David say anything about what he can do?
我们跟委员会谈完 基因局就能介入了
Yeah, once we talk to the Council,then the Bureau can step in.
所以这全靠神秘的委员会了 对吧
So, it all hinges on the mysterious Council, does it?
- 他们不同意怎么办  - 大卫有信心说服他们
- What if they say no? - David is confident that they won't.
大卫 好吧
David, right.
知道吗 我搞清楚自己为什么上不去了
You know, I found out why I can't go upstairs.
我是缺陷者 你是纯净者
I'm "damaged",and you're "pure".
我知道
I know.
你知道 你打算什么时候告诉我
You know.When were you going to tell me?
我不知道
I don't know.I...
- 但我觉得这并不重要  - 为什么不重要
- I guess I didn't think that it matter. - Why doesn't it matter?
因为不管你是纯净者还是缺陷者 都没有任何区别
Because it doesn't make a difference if you're "pure" or  you're "damaged".
对我来说你就是你
You're still the same person to me.
听着 我知道无论如何它都不完美
Look. I know that it's not perfect,by any means, but...
但基因局从边界地带救出了我妈妈 没有他们我也不会来这儿
The Bureau saved my mother from the Fringe.I wouldn't be here without her.
我们真了解他们在那儿做过什么吗
What do you actually know about what they do in the Fringe?
你只是听他们说的
You know what they tell you.
- 是的 但是  - 打扰一下
- Yeah, but... - I'm sorry.
他要你上楼去
He needs you upstairs.
那些人很友好 虽然奇怪 但很友好
Those people are nice,weird, but nice.
是啊 他们确实很奇怪
Yeah. They're definitely weird,that's for sure.
你已经习惯了
You better get used to it.
- 是吗 - 没错
- Really? - Yeah.
下次去边界地带叫上我
Next time you go to the Fringe, I want in.
你还没准备好
You're not ready.
我准备好了
I'm going.
翠丝
Tris.
我注意到 分离对于
I'm more than aware that the separation
你和老四来说的确很困难
has been difficult for you and Four, but...
但我已经观察你们很久了
I've watched you both enough to know that
我想你们该解决一下彼此之间的矛盾
I think the two of you are going to work it out.
我们很好
We're fine.
一直都很好
Everything's fine.
好吧 我们开始工作吧
Good.Let's get to work.
我们走 大家集合
Here we go!Fall in people!
天气晴朗 执行搜捕行动
The weather's clear,we're green for a run!
- 你们行动  我们走  - 快点儿
- You, let's go, let's go! - Come on, come on.
- 我们走 - 准备走
- Move! Let's go! - Get ready to go!
我们走
Let's go!
好了 情况是这样的 听好了
Alright, here's the deal.Listen up!
这是一个人道主义任务
This may be a Humanitarian mission,
但是林代尔据点非常危险
but the dwindle settlement is very dangerous.
- 大家都听清楚了吗  - 清楚
- Everybody clear? - Yes!
- 外面的人平均能活多久  - 25到30年
- So, what's the life span out here? - 25 to 30 years.
如果小时候就被救了 在基因局能活到50到60岁
But if we get people early, they can live up to 50 or 60 in the Bureau.
无畏派 如果是我就不会让你们来这儿
Dauntless, if it's up to me,you would not be out here.
我知道你们觉得芝加哥很危险 但这里更可怕
I know you think it was tough in Chicago, but this is the Fringe.
- 明白吗  - 明白
- Understood? - Yes.
我们的任务是尽可能救更多的孩子
The mission is to save as many kids as possible.
避免他们在恶劣的环境中长大
They grow up in hellish conditions.
虽然你们手上有武器 但不要轻易使用
But, you have your weapons handy,you stick to protocol.
我不想有任何伤亡
I don't want to lose any one.
带上你们的枪
Get out your weapons.
快跑
Come on, let's go!
快 我们要行动了
Go! Go! Go.We got to move!
启动无人机
Drones!
上
Go!
救命
Help!
停下来 好了 没事了
Stop. Stop, stop.Hey, hey, hey. It's okay.
我想见爸爸 求你了
I want my dad.Please!
不 我想要爸爸
No! No!Dad!
没事了 跟着我
Everything will be fine.Let's go. Let's go.
跟我来
Come on!
快跑
Run!
目标搜索中
Searching Target.
这边跑
This way.This way.
目标已确认
Target identified.
快
Go!
- 站住  - 离我们远点儿
- Stop! - Just stay away from us!
- 冷静点儿 我们是来帮你们的  - 我们不需要你们帮助
- Calm down. We're here to help. - We don't need your help.
- 我们想跟你谈谈  - 我不想失去家人
- I just want to talk to you. - I'm not going to lose my family!
站住 不要
Hey!Whoa, whoa, whoa. Stop!
- 放开他 走开 - 放开他
-  Let go! Get away! - Get off him!
放开我的孩子 别碰他
Get off him!Don't touch my boy!
你干了什么
What did you do?
好了 没事了
Come on.It's okay. It's alright.
- 我想见我爸爸  - 我知道
- I want to see my dad. - I know, I know.
老四 我们走 快撤离
Four, let's go!We got to move!
没事了
It's alright.It's okay.
快走 我们要离开了 快撤离
Go!We got to go, we got to go.
我们走 快点儿 快
It's okay.Come on. Come on.
- 罗米特  - 让开
- Romit! - Don't.
究竟发生了什么事
What the hell is going on here?
做好你自己的事 无畏派
Just do you job, Dauntless.
我们走 快点儿
Let's go!Move!
我们走
Let's go!
一个大人 两个孩子 送他们上飞机 快
One man, two children.Get them on the plane, go!
回这儿来
Get back here!
不
No!
你们都闭嘴
I said, shut up.All of you.
- 嘿  - 你 站住
- Hey. - You, stop!
这叫香皂 你应该用用
It's called a soap,you should try it.
怎么了僵尸人 迷路了吗
What's up, Stiff?You lost?
我想找老四
I wanted to see Four.
大卫和我准备去普罗维登斯
David and I are leaving for Providence.
和关系亲密的头儿一起 是吗
On a first name bases with the director, huh?
- 进展得挺快啊  - 皮特 别烦她了
- You work fast. - Peter, can you leave her alone.
我不需要你帮我
I don't need you to defend me.
立正
Attention!
做好去普罗维登斯的准备 一小时之后起飞
Get us ready for Providence.I want my ship within an hour.
- 是 长官  - 跟我来
- Yes, sir. - Follow me.
大卫
David, hey.
我能不能跟你聊聊我的工作
I was wondering if I can talk to you about my job.
你知道 我真的不适合坐办公室
You know, I'm not really a typist and...
如果今天你忙 我能理解
Or if you are busy today, I get it.
没事儿 我们明天再聊也行
Totally fine, we'll talk tomorrow.
好主意
Good idea.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
这在干什么 妮塔
What is this, Nita?
打疫苗
Vaccinations.
打疫苗什么意思 我们几个都没打过疫苗
What do you mean, vaccinations?We weren't given vaccinations.
老四
Four.
看看这个
Look at this.
你叫什么
Hey.What's your name?
我叫什么
My name?
嗨
Hey.
- 你爸爸的事我很难过  - 我爸爸
- I'm sorry about your dad. - My dad?
- 好了 基因局总部见  - 好的
- Alright, I'll see you back at base. - Yep.
这不是人道主义任务
This is not a humanitarian mission.
我们不是在救孩子 而是在绑架
We're not saving kids,we're stealing them.
这就是我们的工作 现在你知道了
This is what we do.Now you know.
大卫从这儿把他们带走
David takes them out from here,
用记忆血清抹掉他们的记忆 让他们在基因局里长大
wipes their memories with the gas,and raises them in the Bureau.
如果抹掉他们的记忆 也就抹掉了他们的身份
If you take away what they know,then you take away who they are.
没错 我想这就是目的
Yeah.I think that's the point.
他们都没有武器
They were all unarmed.
我不会因此投降的
I won't surrender to this.
看看还有没有活着的
Round up anyone who's left.
我们要跟伊芙琳开战
We take the fight to Evelyn.
好 我去装车
Yeah.I'm loading up.
我们马上走
Let's go.
快走
Move it.
今天我们要打倒伊芙琳
Today we take Evelyn down!
不惜一切代价
Whatever it takes!
这是正在发生的事
This is all real time.
他们这儿的监控技术简直了得
I mean, this Surveillance Technology they have in place is extraordinary.
凯莱布 能先别想自己的事儿吗
Caleb, can you get out of your head for a second?
那儿是我们的家
This is our home.
那儿就要开战了
There's going to be a war.
你去哪儿
Where are you going?
得为芝加哥做点儿什么
I'm going to do something about it.
老四 你这是要去干什么
Four, what are you trying to do?
我去找翠丝 我们得离开
Getting Tris.We're leaving.
你不能上去
You can't go up there.
- 你知道自己在干什么吗  - 老四
- What do you think you are doing? - Four!
- 你不能来这儿  - 老四
- You cannot be in here. - Four.
- 这么做没用的  - 纯净
- It's not going to work. - Pure.
中央电梯被侵入了
Central elevator has been compromised.
我们得离开
We're leaving.
- 什么  - 快点儿
- What? - Right now.
什么 我不能走
What?I can't.
听着 你还不了解情况 这些人在骗你
You don't understand yet, but these people have been lying to you.
骗我 你在说什么呢
Lying?What are you talking about?
听着 不管他们说什么 其实他们
Look, whatever they told you.They've been...
放下武器
Put the guns down.
这个大卫他一直都在抢别人的孩子
He's been stealing children from their families.
我们给他们更好的生活
We're giving them a better life.
- 通过杀他们父母  - 那只是个意外 长官
- By killing their parents? - It was an unfortunate accident. Sir.
一个可怕的意外不代表这么做是错的
One terrible accident doesn't mean that it was the wrong thing to do.
翠丝 这个地方跟我们想的不一样
Tris, This is not the place that we thought it was suppose to be.
如果你有能力去救一个人
If you have enough to save one person,
你是选择救健康的孩子还是救生病的老人
and your choice was between a healthy child or a sick old man,
- 你选谁  - 我不会去选择
- who would you choose? - I wouldn't choose!
好吧 那他俩就都死了
Good, now they're both dead.
我们得走了
We have to go.
翠丝 我们得回芝加哥去 我们不应该离开那儿
Tris. We're going back to Chicago, we shouldn't ever have left.
- 不 我们得再等等  - 不 我们一直在等
- No, we have to wait. - Yeah, we've been waiting.
好吗 大卫根本就不是你想的那种人
Okay, David is not the person that you think he is.
老四 你完全不了解大卫
Four, you know nothing about David.
你不了解我们都在这儿忙了些什么
You've no idea what we've been working up here.
你们忙些什么
What have you been working on?
你知道芝加哥现在发生什么了吗
Do you have any idea what is going on out there?
知道 我当然知道
Yes, of course I do.
这就是我们为什么要去见委员会的人
Why do you think we're going to meet with the Council?
翠丝
Tris.
我求你认真听我说
I want you to listen to me.
翠丝
Tris.
跟我回去
You're coming with me.
我得走了
I have to go.
你这么做是错的
You're making a mistake.
准备好了
You ready?
是的
Yeah.
启动自动驾驶
Autopilot engage.
想回芝加哥我带你去
You want to go back to Chicago,I'll take you.
不了 谢谢
No, thanks.
就这么走着穿越边界地带
You want to walk cross the Fringe,I don't think so.
没有规定说你不能回家
There's no rule saying you can't go home, Four.
跟我来
Come on.
- 好吧  - 我和你一起去
- Yeah. - I'll go with you.
准备就绪
All set.
我们去芝加哥
Take us to Chicago.
听着 我理解你的感受
Look, I understand how you're feeling.But...
但是你现在要做的事 对全世界而言将产生巨大的影响
What you're about to do has ramifications for people all over the world.
如果老四不理解 也不要往心里去
If Four doesn't see that,it's not your fault.
大卫根本不想让你看到边界地带的事
David never wanted you to see what you saw, out on the Fringe.
他一直严格控制 没有允许什么都不能做
He keeps tight control.Nothing happens without his approval.
他的飞船是唯一可以穿越伪装墙的
And his ship, is the only one that can fly through the camo wall.
为什么要跟我说这个
Why are you telling me this?
我们不会送你回芝加哥的
We are not taking you to Chicago.
抓紧了
Hold on!
欢迎来到普罗维登斯
Welcome to Providence.
明白他们为什么不愿意分享了
I can see why they don't want to share it.
有一天全世界都会像这儿一样美
Some day, the whole world is going to look this beautiful.
诚如诸位所见 有多种基因标记
So, as you can see,there are multiple
可以支撑这个结论
genetic markers supporting this conclusion.
标准性格测试 行为评估 刺激反应
Standard personality test.Behavioral evaluations. Stimulus response.
她轻而易举地通过了所有的测试
She's passed them all with flying colors.
如果这是真的 听起来确实不错
It all sounds great assuming it's the truth.
菲利普
Phillip.
大卫以前骗过我们 不是吗 大卫
David has lied to us before,haven't you, David?
让这个女孩说说
I like to hear from the girl.
要知道 她可不会为了我而撒谎
Well, I don't know why she can't tell you anything I'm not.
帮个忙 大卫
Indulge us, David.
发现自己是纯净者
This must all come as quite a shock to you, Miss Prior,
对你来说一定很吃惊吧 普勒尔小姐
finding out that you are pure
嗯
Um.
纯净者 我甚至都不知道是什么
Pure. I'm not even sure what's that suppose to mean.
没错 我很吃惊
But yes, it is shocking to me.
我对过去了解得越多就越感觉到
Shocking that the more I learn about the past, the more I feel like...
你们好像一直在犯同一个错误
you're all making the same mistakes over and over again.
- 翠丝 别这么说话  - 让她说 大卫
- Tris, this is not the way. - Let her speak, David.
什么错误 翠丝
What mistakes, Tris?
人类不能用这种方法进行分类
The human beings cannot be categorized in this way.
这是没用的
It doesn't work.
也许是时候接受所有人了 而不是把他们分在不同的群体里
Maybe it's time to start embracing everyone instead of dividing them into groups.
无论他们是纯净者还是缺陷者
Regardless whether they are 'pure' or they are 'damaged'.
- 这不是我们现在要讨论的问题  - 这应该是
- That isn't what we're here to discuss. - Well, it should be.
听着 我知道一切对你们来说是一项实验
Look, I know that all of this is just an experiment to you,
但对芝加哥的人民来说却是真实的
but these people in Chicago are real.
你们创建的派系导致他们现在仍生活在战乱里
And they're in a war right now because of divisions that you created,
而你们却无动于衷
and you are doing nothing to help them.
你要知道大卫才是掌握芝加哥管理权的人
David has control over the administration of Chicago.
他来这儿只是为了增加他的经费
He's only here to extend his funding.
我们乐于做某些事
Which, we would be happy to do,
但如果真像她说得那么差劲 大卫
but if things are as bad as she says, David.
你难道不该先解决一下自家问题吗
Shouldn't you get your house in order first?
你跟我说过你无能为力
You said that you couldn't do anything.
我已经在行动了 我正在重建派别制度
I am doing something.I'm bring back the factions.
什么 为什么
What?Why?
我希望忠诚者能为我解决这个问题
I hope the Allegiant will take care of the problem for me.
派系是有用的 翠丝
The factions work, Tris.
它们围护了和平 成就了你
They keep the peace,they created you.
我真不应该相信你
I never should have trusted you.
你想不牺牲就革命 你想不斗争就迎来和平
You want change with no sacrifice,you want peace with no struggle.
这个世界不是这样的
The world doesn't work like that.
还好吗
You okay?
我还好
I'll be fine.
快到基因局了
I hope the Bureau isn't far.
我要去芝加哥 告诉伊芙琳
I need to get to Chicago,and tell Evelyn
她犯的错误比约翰娜更严重
she's got a lot bigger problem than Johanna.
你需要这个才能穿越伪装墙
You'll need this,to get through the camo wall.
我们需要你的帮助 托比亚斯
We need your help, Tobias.
你不了解大卫的真面目
You don't know what he's capable of.
翠丝怎么办
What about Tris?
只要待在基因局里 她就是安全的
As long as she stays in the Bureau, she's safe.
她对大卫来说很重要
She's too valuable to him.
那我就先走了
I'll need a head start.
大卫问起来
When David asks,
你就跟他说我背叛了你们
I want you to tell him that I left you behind.
好吗
Okay?
- 为什么  - 因为翠丝会知道你在说谎
- Why? - Because Tris will know you're lying.
扫描
纯净 @ 马修.B
允许通行
出了点儿事
There was an accident.
遇到一股气流 虽然没有风暴厉害
There was turbulence, not more than any other storm, but...
也许是闪电
The lightning, maybe.
- 接着飞机就坠毁了  - 老四呢
- We just went down. - Where's Four?
我不知道
I don't know.
我失去意识了 等我醒过来 所有人都死了
I passed out, when I came to,everyone was dead.
老四丢下了我
Four left me behind.
好吧 找找那些据点 在边界地带搜索
Okay, we search the settlement,search the Fringe.
看他在不在那儿
Make sure he's not there.
别担心 会找到的 我保证
Don't worry.We'll find him, I promise.
老四是绝不会在出事后丢下任何人的
Four would never leave anyone behind at the crash site.
没错 他告诉我你一定会这么说的
Yeah.He told me you would say that.
老四这会儿在回芝加哥的路上
Four is trying to make his way back to Chicago.
- 皮特  - 你好 大卫
- Peter. - Hello, David.
我以为你不知道我的名字
I didn't think that you knew my name.
我了解所有芝加哥来的重要人物
I know all of the important people from Chicago.
是吗
Really?
如果我真那么重要
Well, if I'm so important,
为什么你还让我干那么烂的活儿
then why did you give me such a terrible job?
我们都得做出一些牺牲
We all have to make sacrifices.
你也牺牲了
I don't see you making any.
皮特
Peter.
我需要芝加哥那边有人帮我
I need help with something in Chicago.
我能有什么好处
What's in it for me?
如果完成得不错 工作随便你挑
Well, if you do well,you can have any job you want.
除了我的
Except mine.
知道皮特在哪儿吗
Do you know where Peter is ?
不在监控室吗
Uh, he's not in his pod?
不在
No.
不在 那就不知道了
No, I don't know where he is.
还有什么能帮你的吗
Is there something that I can help you with?
帮我找找老四
Can you find Four?
别告诉别人
You can't tell anyone.
好的 没问题
Okay, of course.
都听你的 碧翠丝
Anything you need, Beatrice.
快点儿 老四你在哪儿
Come on, Four, where are you?
伊芙琳 我们在围墙外发现了他
Evelyn.We found him outside the wall.
把面罩摘了
Take it off.
我儿子在哪儿
Where's my son?
我不知道
I don't know.
埃德加告诉了我围墙外的情况
Edgar told me what's out there.
所以你最好说点儿什么 否则我们现在就审判你 说
So you better start talking,or we'll be holding your trial now!
不 你不会的
No, you won't.
因为我有你想要的东西
Because I have something that you need.
是吗 什么东西
Really?And what's that?
能赢得战争的东西
The way to win your war.
有消息吗
Any news?
没有
No.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
翠丝
Tris!
- 找到他了  - 是的 找到了
- Did you find him? - Yes, I found Four.
还有些更让你感兴趣的东西
And there's something else you're going to want to see too.
好了 来吧
Okay, go.
在那儿 就是他 发现他了
Over there!That's him! We got him!
老四
Four.
别担心 他没事 你往下看
Don't worry, he's fine.Just... keep watching.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
你会喜欢它的
You're going to love it.
这是什么
What is it?
试一下 就知道了
Try it out.You'll see.
别用在你喜欢的人身上
Just don't try it on anyone you like.
我一直在想你什么时候才有勇气面对我
I was wondering when you'll have the courage to face me.
我在这儿已经三个星期了
3 weeks you leave me here.
我管理着一个派系
I run a faction!
我保护我们的儿子不受珍宁的迫害
I protected our son from Jeanine's thugs.
你保护他 你管这叫保护
Protected him.Is that what you call it?
暴打你自己的孩子
Beating your own child.
这才成就了今天的他
It made him who he is.
注意控制一下剂量
Make sure he gets a good dose.
托比亚斯 我这么做只想让你变得更好
Tobias, I was trying to make you to be better.
我很抱歉
I'm-I'm sorry, but...
可是你是谁
Who you are?
想象一下如果把这个用在忠诚者身上
Just imagine if you release this on the Allegiant.
甚至连约翰娜也不会记得 你曾经不是这里的领导者
Not even Johanna will remember a time that you weren't in charge.
这个东西是谁给你的
Who exactly told you about this?
在围墙外面有个特别挺你的朋友
You have a very powerful friend on the outside,
只要你选择合作 而不是反抗
if you choose to engage instead of prepare.
- 这位朋友叫什么名字  - 大卫
- Does this friend have a name? - David.
大卫
David?
你可以告诉这位的朋友不到最后一刻我是不会用这东西的
You can tell my friend I'm not going to use that thing unless it's a last resort.
大卫为什么要支持伊芙琳
Why would David support Evelyn?
完全没道理
It doesn't make any sense.
你还好吗 我很担心你
Are you okay?I was worried about you.
伊芙琳 你得跟忠诚者讲和
Evelyn, you need to make peace with the Allegiant.
不 约翰娜已经做出了选择 我从没想过发动战争
No, Johanna made her choice.I never wanted this war.
我会结束它的 我向你保证
But I will end it, I promise you.
你都不知道你的敌人是谁
You have no idea what you are up against.
- 约翰娜不是问题的关键  - 听着
- Johanna is not the issue. - Look.
我知道你还在生我的气 这一点我能理解
I know you're angry at me and I understand that.
我只是 我从来没有
I'm just...I never meant...
现在对我来说也很艰难
This is so hard for me too.
我心里也不想把你关在这儿
I don't want to have to keep you in here.
那就让我出去
Then, let me out.
我做不到 因为这是我的责任
I can't,I have responsibilities.
总有一天你会理解我的 但现在我必须让你待在这儿
One day, you'll understand that,but right now I need you to stay here.
无论发生什么 我都会结束这一切的
I'm going to finish this.One way or another.
你打算怎么结束这一切
How are you going to finish this?
别担心 你不会待太久了
Hey, don't worry.You won't have to be here for long.
你在说什么
What-What are you talking about?
伊芙琳还在拿主意
Well, Evelyn is deciding now,
如果她使用记忆血清 所有人都会忘了自己是谁
If she use the memory serum,Chicago might forget it's own name.
我们得走了
We have to go.
叫上克里斯蒂娜 在外面碰头
Get Christina and meet me outside.
我们去哪儿
Where are we going?
回家
Home.
允许进入
Access granted.
芝加哥那边怎么样了
How's it going in Chicago?
确定伊芙琳她们没有危险的举动吗
Making sure it's safe from Evelyn and the factionless?
翠丝
Tris.
你必须忘了芝加哥
You need to forget about Chicago.
知道吗 这真的很可笑 大卫
You know, it's really funny, David.
你观察我这么多年却一点都不了解我
You've been watching me for years and you don't know anything about me.
你打算清除芝加哥城里所有人的记忆
You're wiping the memories of everyone in Chicago, aren't you?
- 好了 不是  - 你根本就不支持忠诚者
- Alright. Uh... - You were never supporting the Allegiant.
别忘了这些人背叛了你 他们杀了你的父母
These people treated you terribly,they killed your parents.
- 老四就在那儿  - 老四
- Four is there! - Oh, Four.
没错 是的 老四在那儿
Yes. Yes.Four is there.
但他是缺陷者 跟其他人是一样的
But he's "damaged",just like the rest of them.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
坐你的飞船离开 不会再回来了
I'm taking your ship and I'm not come back.
你不会开
You can't fly.
看好了
Watch me.
启动自动驾驶仪
Autopilot engage.
翠丝·普勒尔偷了我的飞船 把她抓回来
Tris Prior is stealing my craft,bring her back.
快点儿
Hurry.
- 克里斯蒂娜 这些给你和翠丝  - 你怎么知道我们要走
- Cristina, these are for you and Tris. - How did you know we were leaving?
你们不是唯一憎恨大卫的人
You're not the only ones who hate David.
- 好了 快点儿  - 谢谢你
- Hey, come on! - Thank you.
- 抓紧  - 快点儿进来
- Hold it! - Get in, get in.
把手拿开 不然把你扔出去
Hands to yourself or I'll throw you out.
我们去救老四
Let's go rescue Four.
有三艘飞船在我们后面
Looks like 3 ships are following us.
- 锁定离子飞行器  - 包围住
- Plasma craft engaged. - Surround her.
让她迫降 自动驾驶仪能让飞船安全着陆
Give her a nudge towards the ground.The autopilot will bring her down safely.
他们想干什么
What are they trying to do?
他们想让我们迫降
They're trying to bring us in for a landing!
我换手动操作
I'm going manual!
- 拉起来  - 试着呢
- Pull up! Pull up! - I'm trying!
试着呢
I'm trying!
注意高度
Altitude
成功了
I got it.
请下令 长官
Your order, sir?
把她击落
Shoot her down.
在她到达伪装墙之前 千万不能让她穿越成功
Before she reaches the camo wall.You can't follow her through.
死定了
We're dead.
我们死定了
We're gonna die!We're gonna die!
坐稳了
Hold on.
我们快到了
We're getting close!
一定可以阻止记忆血清的扩散
There has to be a way to shut off the gas.
看看这些遍布城市的通风系统
Look at the ventilation system,it's all over the city.
看那儿
Down there.
约翰娜
Johanna.
我们来的正是时候
We got here just in time.
是时候了
It's time, Evelyn.
你说过记忆血清是你的最后一招
You said, the gas was a last resort.
你认为对你的审判会是什么结果
How do think your trial is going to end?
血清一旦释放就立刻通知我
Let me know the second the serum is released.
明白 祝你好运
You got it.Good luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
这些无人机怎么用
How do these drones work?
带上头盔
Turn your headgear on.
- 然后呢  - 看好了
- And? - Watch and learn.
站住 放下武器
Stop right there and drop your weapons!
你要干什么
Hey, hey! Whoa!Hey, what are you doing?
放我下去
Put me down!
好了 这个交给你
Alright, this one is on you.
- 小心  - 抱歉
- Easy! - Sorry!
站住 不许动
Stay where you are!
干得漂亮
That's my girl.
侦查
Recon.
那是什么鬼 我不干了
Screw this!I'm out of here!
这是什么
What the hell is that?
嗨
Hey.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我真不应该相信他
I never should have trusted him.
你只是做了你认为对的事
You do what you thought was right.
我爱你
I love you.
我们得找到伊芙琳
We should find Evelyn.
来吧
Come on.
血清准备就绪
Serum Status: Ready.
现在
Now.
如果你按下按钮
If you press that button,
我们在这儿是绝对安全的
We're complete safe inside the vault.
而且
And...
没人知道发生了什么
No one else will ever know what happen to them.
自己选吧
Your choice.
血清气化启动
Initialize: Serum vaporization
伙计们 听着 他们启动了血清气化程序
Guys. Guys.They just initiated the serum.
找到关闭方法了吗
Did you find a way to shut it off?
还没有
Not yet.
这边走
This way.
锁住了
It's locked.
我看看能不能从控制室打开它
I'll see if I can get into the Control room.
伊芙琳 你现在必须马上关了它
Evelyn, you have to stop this right now.
我
I...
我本来不想这么做 但是我别无选择
I do want to do this,but I have to.
我是唯一知道如何拯救芝加哥的人
I'm the only one who knows how to save Chicago.
我关上城门是对的 但是没有一个人听
I was right to close the gate,but no one listened!
没有
No one!
甚至连你也不听
Not even you.
这都是忠诚者他们逼我这么干的
The Allegiant, brought this on themselves.
伊芙琳 记忆血清不光会清除忠诚者们的记忆
Evelyn, that serum is not just going to wipe the memories of the Allegiant.
还会清除所有人的记忆
It's going to do it to the whole city.
什么
What?
那些人对你撒了谎
Whatever they told you was a lie.
什么
What...
- 拜托 - 伊芙琳
- Come on - Evelyn.
我来是想帮你的
I want to stand by your side.
如果城市被你毁了
But what you do to the city...
我也一样
... you do to me.
妈妈
Mom.
托比亚斯
Tobias.
我会想不起你是谁
I won't know who you are.
停手吧
Don't do it.
求你了
Please.
不要
Don't
不
No!
你选择我这样的真是明智之举
That's why he picked a guy like me for a job like this.
我希望你正在看着 大卫
I hope you're watching, David!
克里斯蒂娜 找到开门的方法了吗
Cristina, have you figured out the door yet?
门一旦从里面锁上就打不开了
Once it's locked from the inside,the door won't open.
再试试
Well, keep trying!
开始释放血清
Begin serum release.
不要吸入这气体
Don't breathe it in!Don't breathe in the gas!
凯莱布 我们现在走投无路了
Caleb, we're running out of option here!
淡定 我想我找到办法了
Hold on.I think I found something.
这儿有个气体扩散的咽喉点
There's a choke point where the vapor gets pumped out.
切断他们之间的无线电
Cut their comm line to the ship.
凯莱布
Caleb?
- 凯莱布  - 翠丝
- Caleb? - Tris?
翠丝 听得见吗
Tris, can you hear me?
凯莱布
Caleb!
我要进去了
I'm going in.
什么
What!
该死
Oh shit!
怎么了
What the...
- 快关上它  - 锁住了
- Make it stop! - It's locked!
- 快开门  - 快开门
- Open the door! - Open the door!
皮特 快开门
Peter, open the door!
我会抓住你的 皮特
I will find you, Peter.
托比亚斯
Tobias.
没事了
You're okay.
该死
Damn it!
- 能关掉吗  - 不行
- Can you stop it? - No.
凯莱布 听得见吗
Caleb, do you hear me?
凯莱布 你在哪儿
Caleb, where are you?
凯莱布·普勒尔
Caleb Prior!
抱歉
Sorry.
继续跟着我
Keep going.Stay with me.
翠丝 看看这个 非常精确
Tris, look at this.It's really smart.
它们顺着通风管在空气中扩散
So, they ran the pipe into the air duck.
凯莱布 说重点 薄弱点在哪儿
Caleb, focus.Just tell me where it is.
就在这儿 这儿有个独立阀门控制空气流通
It's right here. There's an isolation valve that controls the flow of the air.
但我不知道怎么去那儿
But, I don't know how you're going to get down there.
我来 老四
I do.Four!
走
Go!
翠丝 在走廊的尽头
Tris, it's at the end of the hall.
关上门
Close the doors.
翠丝 我控制着一切事物
Tris, I control everything.
我甚至能立刻把你锁在这个房间里
I can even seal the room you're in right now.
直到你停止反抗
Just stop fighting.
还有一条路 下楼梯
There's another way.Down the stairs.
真是愚蠢 打住吧 我造就了你
This is foolish, just stop.I made you.
你就像我的孩子一样 你现在的一举一动
You might as well be my child.Which is what you're acting like.
淘气得都没边儿了
A spoil child.
翠丝 在走廊尽头 有另外一条路可以到梯子那儿
Tris, at the end of the hall.There's another way on the left.
都结束了 翠丝
It's over, Tris.
搜索目标
Searching target.
目标已确认
Target identified.
找到了
There you are.
你说得对 大卫 都结束了
You're right, David.It is over.
不
NO!
血清释放终止
Serum release halted.
缺陷者表现如何
How's that for "damaged".
安全
Clear.
安全了
It's clear.
安全
Clear.
成功了
We did it.
这才是该为家人做的
That's what you do for family.
凯莱布 还有件事你得帮我去做
Caleb, there's one more thing I want you to do.
我想给大卫发条信息
I want to send a message to David.
我是翠丝·普勒尔
My name Tris Prior.
我今天在这儿要揭露一个真相
And I'm here to reveal the truth.
这个星球上的确还有其他人类存在
There are others who exist on this planet
可他们并没有平等地对待我们
They do not view us as equals.
他们称自己为纯净者 称我们为缺陷者
They called themselves the "Pure",and they called us the "damaged".
他们用围墙将我们与他们隔离开来
They created a wall to divide us from their world.
用派系将我们彼此分开
And factions to divide us from each other.
有人吗 得了
Hello!Come on!
你觉得这样就能把我一脚踢开是吗
You think you can ditch me like this?
让我替你干尽那些缺德事
You got me to do your dirty work
然后像甩掉他们一样想把我也甩掉
and then just, wiped me away like the rest of them!
我们不是说好的吗 朋友
We had a deal, pal!
我们成了试验品 这几乎毁了我们
We're their experiment,and it almost destroyed us.
我把自动驾驶仪设在了我们朋友的附近
I set the autopilot right for our friend's neighbourhood.
当它穿越伪装墙的时候会给他们一个小小的惊喜
Along with a little surprise when it goes through the camouflage wall.
他们企图让我们忘记自己是谁
They tried to make us forget who we are
来自何处 但他们没有成功
and where we're from,but they did not succeed.
所以我们能站在这儿团结一致
So, here we stand together,
不是作为五大派系 而是作为一座城市
not as 5 factions,but as one city.
我们要推翻他们建立的围墙
We're gonna tear down their wall.
怎么了
Hey.What's going on?
我就想住顶楼
I want the penthouse!
是的 没错
Yeah, that's right!
或者
Or...
跟上面一样酷的房间也行
a room in that really cool upstairs area.
好吧 听着
Okay, look!
我会回我以前住的地方去的
I'll even take my old bunk back!
只要快点把这该死的门给我打开
Just come on and open the damn door!
求你了
Please!
过去你们看着我们 现在我们看着你们
You've seen us,and now, we see you.
墙外的人你们现在听好了
To those of you beyond the wall,
我知道你们正在听
hear me loud and clear,because I know you are listening.
芝加哥不是你们的实验室
Chicago is not your experiment.
它是我们的家园
It is our home.
永远都是
And it always will be.
-= 谢谢观赏 =-